## Adithya Ajith | Software Developer

Address: 1435 Woodbine Avenue, Toronto, ON M4C4G8

Phone: +1-437-2217-180

Email: ajithadithya38@gmail.com

### Summary

Experienced Software Engineering professional with a bachelor's degree in computer science from India's top engineering school and a post-graduation degree in big data architecture in Canada. I acquired a strong knowledge of full-stack development during my one-year work term in a fast-paced startup environment. I'm well capable of working under pressure, learning new technologies, team management, problem-solving, and possess good communication skills.

#### **Skills & Abilities**

Programming: Java, C++, Python, R

Web Technologies: JavaScript, Typescript, Cassandra, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, Hadoop,

Web services(REST), AWS, Jenkins.

Frameworks: Angular, Ionic, Spring boot.

**Operating Systems:** Linux, Windows.

Database: MySQL, MS SQL, Mongo DB.

IDE: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Spyder.

#### **Experience**

## PEER TUTOR | FANSHAWE COLLEGE, LONDON ONTARIO FROM SEPTEMBER 2019 - May 2020

Helping students with doubts in Java.

One on one assistance to students for exams, projects and other course works.

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | IPRIMED EDUCATION SOLUTIONS, BANGALORE INDIA FROM JUNE 2018 - APRIL 2019

Worked on both frontend and backend development to build an e-learning platform.

Implemented mobile Application.

Used Angular 5 to develop Single Page Applications.

Followed Agile methodologies with end to end CI/CD pipeline by integration tools Jenkins and AWS.

Hands on defect tracking using JIRA

Supported multiple projects simultaneously, troubleshooting and debugging.

#### **Education**

Post Graduation in Big Data Solution Architecture | Conestoga College | Waterloo, Ontario | 2020 May - 2020 Dec

Completed courses in Python, R for Data Analysis, Sql and noSql programming, Hadoop for Big Data.

# POST GRADUATION IN SOFTWARE & INFORMATION SYSTEMS TESTING | FANSHAWE COLLEGE | LONDON, ONTARIO | 2019 May - 2019 Dec

Completed courses in Java for development project management, Systems design and analysis, test automation, and Security screening.

# BTECH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING | NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY | KERALA, INDIA | 2014 SEPT - 2018 SEPT

Acquired thorough knowledge in Object Oriented Programming, Web development, Software engineering, Data structures and algorithms, and Data mining.

### **Projects**

### CO-FOUNDER | FIWE, KERALA INDIA | JAN 2020 - PRESENT

Developed android and iOS apps using Ionic and Angular.

Developed REST services using JAVA

Implemented MYSQL database

Experienced version control systems using GIT and Maven.

#### Certification

MACHINE LEARNING A-ZTM: HANDS ON PYTHON AND R IN DATA SCIENCE | UDEMY ACADEMY